import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Bacteria belong to kingdom",
A: "Animalia",
B: "Fungi",
C: "Prokaryotae",
D: "Protoctista",
answer: "C. Prokaryotae",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. In a simple electric circuit the device that regulates the current flow is the",
A: "ammeter",
C: "resistor",
D: "rheostat",
answer: "C. resistor",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Which of the following organism is  a producer",
A: "Grasshopper",
B: "Spirogyra",
C: "Rhizopus",
D: "Virus",
answer: "B. Spirogyra",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Examples of hydrocarbons belongs to alkane series are",
A: "C2H6 and C3H8",
B: "C2H2 and C3H6",
C: "C2H8 and C4H8",
D: "C4H10 and C2H4",
answer: "A. C2H6 and C3H8",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Green manure is beneficial to the soil if the plant material is",
A: "free from pest",
B: "grown with fertilizer",
C: "ploughed into moist soil just before flowering",
D: "Ploughed into moist soil after harvesting",
answer: "C. ploughed into the most soil just before flowering",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Lactic acid can be found in",
A: "grape",
B: "orange",
C: "palm oil",
D: "sour milk",
answer: "D. sour milk",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. Evaporation of a liquid increase with",
A: "decrease in density of the liquid",
B: "increase in atmospheric acid",
C: "decrease in the exposed surface area",
D: "decrease in temperature",
answer: "A. decrease in density of the liquid",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Which of the following process is a physical change",
A: "Electrolysis of aqueous sodium chloride",
B: "Fermentation of palm wine",
C: "Separation of sand and water",
D: "Burning of magnesium ribbon in air",
answer: "C. Separation of sand from water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Soil conservation can be achieved through",
A: "agroforestry",
B: "intercropping",
C: "mixed cropping",
D: "introduction of green legumes",
answer: "A. agroforestry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. A laterally inverted image is one which is",
A: "real and formed in front of the mirror",
B: "real and formed behind the mirror",
C: "vitual and formed behind the mirror",
D: "virtual and formed in front of the mirror.",
answer: "C. virtual and formed behind the mirror",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Killing water snails with molluscides results in the control of",
A: "ascariasis",
B: "onchocerciasis",
C: "schistosomiasis",
D: "trypanosomiasis",
answer: "C. schistosomiasis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The vacuum between the two walls in a vacuum flask minimizes heat transfer by \nI. conduction\nII. convection\nIII. radiation\nWhich of the above statements is / are correct",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. An atom of element X is made up 17 of electrons and 18 neutrons. What is the mass number of the element?",
A: "17",
B: "18",
C: "34",
D: "35",
answer: "D. 35",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Biodiversity is defined as",
A: "study of living things",
B: "variation in forms of life",
C: "classification of living things",
D: "living and non-things in habitats.",
answer: "B. variation in forms of life",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Which of the following methods is/are used in making magnets? \nI. single touch \nII. Double touch \nIII. Electrical",
A: "I only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. the MOST effective method of reducing erosion on hilly lands is by",
A: "terracing",
B: "applying organic manure",
C: "creating wind breaks",
D: "erection of barriers.",
answer: "A. terracing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Which of the following features does NOT adapt a leaf of a flowering plant for photosynthesis",
A: "being thin in shape",
B: "being flat and broad",
C: "possession of starch",
D: "possession of numerous stomata",
answer: "C. Possession of starch",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Steel is preferred to pure iron for constructional work because",
A: "steel is cheaper than iron",
B: "steel is harder and stronger than iron",
C: "iron poses more health hazard than steel",
D: "steel is more shiny than iron",
answer: "B. steel is harder and stronger than iron",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
instruction: "The diagram below is an illustration of NPN transistor\nStudy it carefully and answer questions 19 to 20",
id: "question19",
question: "19. The part labelled I is",
A: "base",
B: "collector",
C: "emitter",
D: "resistor",
answer: "B. collector",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. The function of the part labelled II is to supply",
A: "protons",
B: "voltages",
C: "negative charges",
D: "position charges",
answer: "C. negative charges",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. A tall maize plant with genotype TT is crossed with a short maize plant with genotype it. What will be the genotype of their offspring?",
A: "50% TT",
B: "50%tt",
C: "100%Tt",
D: "100%TT",
answer: "C. 100% TT",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. The clustering together of chicks under the hover in a brooder house is an indication that",
A: "a foreign object has come into the brooder house",
B: "there is insufficient illumination in the brooder house",
C: "the temperature in the brooder house is very low",
D: "there is outbreak of disease.",
answer: "C. the temperature in the brooder house is very low",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. A strong acid is one which",
A: "has a low corrosive power",
B: "has a low concentration of water",
C: "gives high concentration of hydrogen ions in solution",
D: "gives high concentration of hydroxide ions in solution.",
answer: "C. gives high concentration of hydrogen ions in solution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Which of the following signs are associated with parturition in pigs\nI. udder drops\nII. teats become pinkish-red in colour\nIII. valva slackens\nIV. inability to squeeze milk out of treats",
A: "I and IV only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I, II and IV only",
D: "I, II and IIII only.",
answer: "D. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Salting of fish for preservation uses the principles of",
A: "diffusion",
B: "osmosis",
C: "plasmolysis",
D: "active transport.",
answer: "B. osmosis",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The efficiency of a machine is less than 100% due to",
A: "the work done against friction",
B: "the work when operating it",
C: "the greater load to effort ratio",
D: "its high mechanical advantage",
answer: "A. the work done against friction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Which of the following pairs of compounds will produce an ester when warned with few drops of concentrated sulphuric acid",
A: "Ethanol and Ethane",
B: "Ethanol and Ethanoic acid",
C: "Ethane and Ethanoic acid",
D: "Ethanoic acid and Ethane",
answer: "B. Ethanol and ethanoic acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The use of watering can is necessary in crop production",
A: "after harvesting of the field crops",
B: "during rainy season",
C: "when the crops are the nursey stage",
D: "when the farm is far from the source of water",
answer: "C. when the crops are at the nursery stage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Ultrafiltration in the Boowmanâ€™s  capsule of a mammalian kidney results from",
A: "afferent arteriole being longer than the efferent arteriole",
B: "afferent arteriole being wider than the efferent arteriole",
C: "efferent arteriole being wider than afferent arteriole",
D: "efferent arteriole being longer than the afferent arteriole",
answer: "B. afferent arteriole being wider than the efferent arteriole",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. A car travelling at uniform speed of 40.0ms-1 covers the distance between two statin in 2.0 minutes. Determine the  distance between two stations",
A: "0.2km",
B: "2.4km",
C: "4.8km",
D: "8.0KM",
answer: "C. 4",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Which of the following prosesses is associated with rusting of iron?it",
A: "is a physical change",
B: "take place in the presence of dry air",
C: "release carbon dioxide",
D: "produce an oxide of iron",
answer: "D. produces an oxide of iron",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Aristotle classification of living things was based on the",
A: "appearance and movement of the organism",
B: "structural similarities and differences of the organism",
C: "anatomical and histological differences",
D: "evolutionary trend of the organism",
answer: "A. appearance and movement of the organisms",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Which of the following crops is stored in barns",
A: "cassava",
B: "cowpea",
C: "pineapple",
D: "yam",
answer: "D. Yam",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Which of the following statement about the diagram below is correct",
A: "position Y is called penumbra",
B: "illustrates an eclipse of sun",
C: "position Y is called umbra",
D: "illustrates an eclipse of  moon",
answer: "A. Position X is called penumbra",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. The test of hydrogen in the laboratory is",
A: "a characteristic irritating smell",
B: "a â€˜popâ€™ sound produce with glowing splint",
C: "producing a pungent smell",
D: "rekindling of glowing splints",
answer: "B. a â€˜popâ€™ sound produced with a glowing splint",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Fats and oils are esters formed from reaction between",
A: "glycerine and long chain fatty acids",
B: "glycerol and long chain fatty acids",
C: "glycerine and sodium hydroxide",
D: "glycerol and sodium hydroxide",
answer: "B. glycerol and long chain fatty acids",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following substances is present in both glomerular filtrate and urine",
A: "Glucose",
B: "Urea",
C: "Amino acids",
D: "Blood proteins.",
answer: "B. Urea",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. A piece of metal of volume of 25cm3 has a mass of 45g. determine its density in kgm3",
A: "0.56 x 103 kgm3",
B: "1.80 x 103 kg m3",
C: "5.66 x 103 kgm3",
D: "1.80 x 104 kgm3",
answer: "B. 1",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Land and sea breezes occur as a result of",
A: "conventional currents",
B: "the different positions of the moon",
C: "the revolution of the earth",
D: "heat transfer by land.",
answer: "A. convectional currents",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Which of the following statements about inhaled air and exhaled air is correct",
A: "Exhaled air contains more oxygen than inhaled air",
B: "Inhaled air contains same amount of oxygen as in exhaled air",
C: "Inhaled air contains more carbon dioxide than exhaled air.",
D: "Exhaled air contains more carbon dioxide than inhaled air.",
answer: "D. Exhaled air contains more carbon dioxide than inhaled air",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Sound energy can be converted into an electrical energy by",
A: "amplifier",
B: "loudspeaker",
C: "microphone",
D: "radio",
answer: "C. microphone",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. An onion bulb can be describe as one which",
A: "grows horizontally underground and has long internodes.",
B: "grows obliquely from an underground parts of the parent plant",
C: "has fibrous roots arising from the base and a short conical stem that grows vertically.",
D: "has thick, horizontal stem and adventitious roots arising from the noes",
answer: "C. has fibrous roots arising from the base and a short conical stem that grows vertically",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following effects are associated with late harvesting of maize. \nI Increase in crop yield \nII. Rain may cause again to rot \nIII. Weevils may attack and destroy grain \nIV. Exposure of maize to attacks by birds and rodents.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV only.",
answer: "D. II, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. A quantity of NaCl was dissolved in 100.0 cm3 of solution to obtain 0.5 M NaCl solution. Determine the mass NaCl used. (Na = 23, Cl= 35.5)",
A: "2.93 g",
B: "5.85 g",
C: "29.25 g",
D: "58.50 g",
answer: "A. 2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The scrotum of a human is located externally because",
A: "it will have limited space in the abdomen",
B: "it will take too much space in the abdomen",
C: "the temperature for sperm production should be higher than the body temperature",
D: "the temperature for sperm production should be lower than the body temperature.",
answer: "D. the temperature for sperm production should be lower than the body temperature",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
instruction: "The diagram below warns of hazard study it carefully and answer questions 46 and 47.",
id: "question46",
question: "46. What does the diagram signify",
A: "Corrosive",
B: "Explosive",
C: "Irritant",
D: "Highly inflammable",
answer: "C. Irritant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. A substance which can be associated with this hazard illustrated is",
A: "ethanol",
B: "x-ray",
C: "gunpowder",
D: "hydrogen peroxide",
answer: "A. ethanol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The human eye blinks when bright light is shown on it because",
A: "of delayed response",
B: "the action is initiated from the cerebrum",
C: "it is an automatic response",
D: "it is under the control of the cerebrum.",
answer: "C. it is an automatic response",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. An example of an ectoparasite is",
A: "housefly",
B: "tapeworm",
C: "tick",
D: "liver fluke",
answer: "C. tick",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The true stomach of a ruminant is the",
A: "abomasum",
B: "omasum",
C: "reticulum",
D: "rumen.",
answer: "A. abomasum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},



]